ENRIQUE HERREROS

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Madrid, Spain

PHONE

+34-676-86-23-99

EMAIL

eherrerosj@gmail.com

DATE OF BIRTH

May-1990

NATIONALITY

Spanish & Canadian

SOCIAL

eherreros.com

LinkedIn

Twitter

<u>Medium</u>

SKILLS

Python

Machine Learning

Deep Learning

Django

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Keras / PyTorch

SQL

Docker

Pandas / Sklearn / Numpy

Kubernetes

Linux

LANGUAGES

English: mother tongue Spanish: mother tongue

HOBBIES

Kitesurf, paddle tennis, biking, swimming, kaggle, reading and cinema

PROFILE

6+ years experienced ML Engineer with proven success in building and deploying algorithms, predictive models and bringing ideas to reality. Passionate, curious and quick-learner, I bring experience from small, medium and large companies, which taught me to quickly zoom in from the whole picture to low-level details. I thrive when immersed in high-skilled technical teams. Kaggle Expert (top 3% in the world).

EXPERIENCE

CTO & Co-Founder

Shalion

April 2019 - June 2021 Barcelona

Co-Founded Shalion, a web SaaS that helps top-tier brands monitor their ecommerce performance. Developed from scratch and deployed the backend, machine learning algorithms, web scrapers and infrastructure of all 3 products. Hired and led a team of developers, which were key to grow from 0 to 500K€ ARR and from 3 to 20 employees in <2yrs.

Stack: Python, AWS, Django REST, Scrapy, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Sentry, sklearn

Machine Learning Engineer & Co-Founder

Feb 2018 - Sept 2019 Madrid

Xplore.ai

Co-Founded Xplore.ai, a ML consultancy company. I engineered and deployed ML and Deep Learning solutions for clients like BBVA, Mango, FindHotel or Smart Protection, allowing the company to grow from 0 to +150K€ revenue in the first year. Was accepted at Telefónica Open Future startup incubator. Spinoff into Shalion.

Stack: Python, Keras, PyTorch, AWS, Docker, Flask, SQL

Machine Learning Engineer

<u>FindHotel</u>

Jan 2017 - June 2018 Amsterdam

Built the main ML algorithms from scratch for a hotel booking marketplace with +150K customers/month. Developed: (1) hotel recommender, which significantly increased conversions; (2) booking cancellation prediction model, (3) price prediction model, that was key for inventory reselling.

Stack: XGBoost, Random Forest, kNN, KD-Tree. Prod: AWS Batch, API Gateway, Docker and Jenkins

Data Scientist

June 2014 - Sept 2016 Madrid

Deloitte Madrid

Consultated a large insurance company in Spain in IT risks projects. Developed ad-hoc fraud detection and prevention tools and models that allowed fraud

reduction by +3MM€. Stack: Python, scikit-learn, Splunk, SQL, jQuery

EDUCATION

MSc. Data Science, CUM LAUDE

Sept 2016 - Sept 2017 Amsterdam

University of Amsterdam

Thesis: "Hotel Booking Cancellation Modeling using ML"

BSc. Communication Systems Engineering

Sept 2008 - Dec 2013 Madrid

Universidad Carlos III de Madrid

<u>Thesis</u> passed with distinction: "Platform for Analysis, Monitoring and Web Visualization of 802.11 Traffic"